# JACK BARKER

## JackBarker118@gmail.com 553 Rolling Hills Rd • Coppell, Texas 75019 • (940) 536-8081

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To find meaningful work in the medical industry using my experience, expertise and education. I worked with medical professionals to increase my knowledge of the healthcare industry while learning valuable information on the fundamentals of business as well as life sciences.

#### **EDUCATION**

**The University of Texas at Austin**Bachelor of Science and Arts, Biology

December 2020

Minor: Business Foundations

Overall GPA: 3.36

## **EXPERIENCE**

Texas Orthopedics Sports and Rehabilitation Associates - Clinical Analyst; Austin, Texas

June 2018 - January 2020

- Assisted an orthopedic surgeon during 114 clinical hours
- Assisted in diagnosing patients and examined the progress of follow up patients
- Observed surgeries including ACL repair, Rotator Cuff Reconstruction, Patellar Tendon Repair, and Shoulder, Ankle and Knee Arthroscopy
- Witnessed use of Arthrex's Graftlink technology

**Uber** - Food Delivery Driver; Austin/Dallas, Texas

June 2019 - January 2020

- Maintained, acquired and delivered orders for 55 customers
- Facilitating communication between multiple parties: uber, the restaurant, and the customer; ensuring optimal order delivery every time

### Andrews Institute for Orthopedics & Sports Medicine – Clinical Analyst; Plano, Texas

July 2017 – August 2017

- Assisted a Scoliosis Orthopedic Surgeon during 26 of his clinical hours
- Assisted in diagnosing patient spinal curves along with other orthopedic issues and examining the progress of follow up patients
- Observed surgeries including TBT ACL Repair, and Scoliosis Spine Revision Surgery

Twisted root burger co. - Busboy; Coppell, Texas

May 2016 - August 2016

- · Maintained table settings by removing courses, replacing utensils and refilling beverages promptly and courteously
- Worked in the kitchen cleaning dishes

#### **LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE AND ACTIVITIES**

Seton Ascension Foundations – Volunteer; Austin, Texas

May 2019 - December 2020

- Volunteered at the Dell Seton at the University of Texas at Austin and Seton Medical center Austin
- Organized patient charts in the Pre-operative Admissions Testing Department; ensuring they and their surgeons had all the correct paperwork in prior to surgery
- Addressed patients general needs in the emergency room; coordinating nurses, distributing blankets, snacks or water, and facilitating patient transportation via wheel chairs
- Maintained exam room in the emergency department; cleaned all surfaces, threw away trash, disposed of sharps/biohazardous wastes, and replaced sheets

**Sigma Phi Epsilon** – *Member; Texas Alpha Chapter* 

August 2016 – May 2020

- Member of the House and Social committees, responsible for planning and organizing events at the house
- Helped raise funds for various charities, such as; Lonestar Paralysis Foundation, Grace Loncar Foundation, Nancy-Jane Tucker-David memorial scholarship
- Maintained active involvement in the organization while still excelling in my school, work and volunteer efforts

### Children's Health Junior Leadership Board - Member

August 2013 - May 2016

- Select group of students with the goal to raise money for the Children's Cancer Fund
- Organized volunteer opportunities for high school students the Dallas, Tx area

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Computer Skills: [Proficient] R studio, MS Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Languages: conversational in Spanish

Interests: Football, Basketball, Tennis, Skiing, Wake boarding and Surfing, Hiking, Cooking